VLADISLAV KIBAKOV

+77014870570 vladislav.kibakov@gmail.com vladislav-kibakov.github.io Temirtau, Kazakhstan

Automation & Controls Engineer with 5 years' experience in maintenance of industrial automation systems and developing/implementing new ones as commercial projects. In-depth knowledge of PLC / HMI / SCADA (DCS) programming. Able to work with automation devices from many manufacturers. Looking to fill a position of an in-house Automation & Controls Engineer, but ready to consider other options.

Experience

Senior Programming Engineer

Kazcentrnaladka / TechnoAutomatica LLP Oct 2017 - Present

- Ensure troubleproof operation of automation equipment of enrichment plant of the largest copper producer in Kazakhstan — Kazakhmys Corporation LLC. The production rate of the plant is processing 3,500,000 tons of copper ore per year. Continuous production
- Manage 37 PLCs, 13 HMIs, 2 SCADA servers, 3000 D(I/O) / A(I/O) signals as the only PLC Programmer on the plant. This includes troubleshooting, editing code or writing projects from scratch
- Implemented 4 commercial projects worth from 4000\$ up to 75000\$ in mining and manufacturing industries. In addition, make on my initiative modernizations projects free of costs by using existing or old/unused equipment to increase trouble-free uptime or production rate of the plant. For details on projects visit my website vladislav-kibakov.github.io
- Automate new technological equipment and integrate it into the existing automation system. Such as new pumps, compressors, conveyors

Junior Automation Engineer KAZCENTRELECTROPROVOD LLP Aug 2016 - Oct 2017

- Ensured troubleproof operation of automation equipment of the cable production factory. This includes sensors, regulators, VFDs, PLCs, HMIs, SCADAs. The scale of the factory is 20 cable production lines, 26 "Twisting in a pair" machines, and additional units, such as press and rewinding machines
- Edited the program code of PLC / HMI / SCADA
- Implemented measurement and display of the length of the produced cable and linear speed on 2 old cable production lines

Skills

Non-technical skills:

- Teamwork and communication skills
- · Ability to work independently
- workflow

Technical skills:

- PLC / HMI / SCADA (DCS) programming Mitsubishi, Siemens, Delta
- Industrial Networks Profibus DP, CC link IE, Modbus RTU/TCP, OPC DA/UA
- Self-study, ability to learn new technologies VFDs Mitsubishi, Yaskawa, Delta
- Self-motivation and a desire to improve the Projects research, design, installation, programming, commissioning
 - Python / Databases completed courses

Education

Master of Engineering and Technology in Automation and Control

Karaganda State Technical University, 2016–2018

Educational program — Robotics & Control systems GPA — 3.72/4.0

The diploma is accredited by World Education Services

Bachelor of Engineering and Technology in Electric Power Engineering

Karaganda State Technical University, 2012–2016

Educational program — Electric drive and automation of mining technological complexes

GPA — 3.72/4.0

The diploma is accredited by World Education Services

Languages

English: IELTS 7.5/9 (CEFR — C1)

Russian: Native

Interests

Training, Soccer, Pro-Wrestling, Video Games, Books